<?xml version="1.0"?>
<chapter id="conclusion">
  <chapterinfo>
    <mediaobject condition="pdf">
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="images/chap-conclusion.png" scalefit="1"/>
      </imageobject>
    </mediaobject>
    <keywordset>
      <keyword>Future</keyword>
      <keyword>Improvements</keyword>
      <keyword>Opinions</keyword>
    </keywordset>
  </chapterinfo>
  <title>Conclusion: Debian's Future</title>
  <highlights>
    <para>The story of Falcot Corp ends with this last chapter; but Debian
    lives on, and the future will certainly bring many interesting
    surprises.</para>
  </highlights>
  <section id="sect.upcoming-developments">
    <title>Upcoming Developments</title>

    <para>Weeks (or months) before a new version of Debian is released, the
    Release Manager picks the codename for the next version. Now that
    Debian version 8 is out, the developers are already busy working on
    the next version, codenamed <emphasis
    role="distribution">Stretch</emphasis>…</para>

    <para>There is no official list of planned changes, and Debian never
    makes promises relating to technical goals of the coming versions.
    However, a few development trends can already be noted, and we can try
    some bets on what might happen (or not).</para>

    <para>In order to improve security and trust, most if not all the
    packages will be made to build reproducibly; that is to say, it
    will be possible to rebuild byte-for-byte identical binary
    packages from the source packages, thus allowing everyone to
    verify that no tampering has happened during the builds.</para>

    <para>In a related theme, a lot of effort will have gone into
    improving security by default, and mitigating both “traditional”
    attacks and the new threats implied by mass surveillance.</para>

    <para>Of course, all the main software suites will have had a
    major release.  The latest version of the various desktops will
    bring better usability and new features.  Wayland, the new display
    server that is being developed to replace X11 with a more modern
    alternative, will be available (although maybe not default) for at
    least some desktop environments.
    </para>

    <!-- Not relevant for Stretch as far as I can tell (Lolando 2015-10-01)
    <para>New architectures may be introduced, and others may be
    abandoned, depending on the availability of hardware and
    porters.</para> -->

    <para>A new feature of the archive maintenance software,
    “bikesheds”, will allow developers to host special-purpose package
    repositories in addition to the main repositories; this will allow
    for personal package repositories, repositories for software not
    ready to go into the main archive, repositories for software that
    has only a very small audience, temporary repositories for testing
    new ideas, and so on.</para>

  </section>
  <section id="sect.future-of-debian">
    <title>Debian's Future</title>

    <para>In addition to these internal developments, one can reasonably
    expect new Debian-based distributions to come to light, as many
    tools keep making this task easier. New specialized
    subprojects will also be started, in order to widen Debian's reach to
    new horizons.</para>

    <para>The Debian user community will increase, and new contributors
    will join the project… including, maybe, you!</para>

    <para>The Debian project is stronger than ever, and well on its way
    towards its goal of a universal distribution; the inside joke within
    the Debian community is about <foreignphrase>World
    Domination</foreignphrase>.</para>

    <para>In spite of its old age and its respectable size, Debian keeps on
    growing in all kinds of (sometimes unexpected) directions. Contributors
    are teeming with ideas, and discussions on development mailing lists,
    even when they look like bickerings, keep increasing the momentum.
    Debian is sometimes compared to a black hole, of such density that any
    new free software project is attracted.</para>

    <para>Beyond the apparent satisfaction of most Debian users, a deep
    trend is becoming more and more indisputable: people are increasingly
    realising that collaborating, rather than working alone in their corner, leads to
    better results for everyone. Such is the rationale used by
    distributions merging into Debian by way of subprojects.</para>

    <para>The Debian project is therefore not threatened by
    extinction…</para>
  </section>
  <section id="sect.future-of-this-book">
    <title>Future of this Book</title>

    <para>We would like this book to evolve in the spirit of free software.
    We therefore welcome contributions, remarks, suggestions, and
    criticism. Please direct them to Raphaël
    (<email>hertzog@debian.org</email>) or Roland
    (<email>lolando@debian.org</email>). For actionable feedback,
    feel free to open bug reports against the <literal>debian-handbook</literal>
    Debian package. The website will be used to gather
    all information relevant to its evolution, and you will find there
    information on how to contribute, in particular if you want
    to translate this book to make it available to an even
    larger public than today.
    <ulink type="block" url="http://debian-handbook.info/"/></para>

    <para>We tried to integrate most of what our experience at Debian
    taught us, so that anyone can use this distribution and take the best
    advantage of it as soon as possible. We hope this book contributes to
    making Debian less confusing and more popular, and we welcome publicity
    around it!</para>

    <para>We would like to conclude on a personal note. Writing (and
    translating) this book took a considerable amount of time out of our
    usual professional activity. Since we are both freelance consultants,
    any new source of income grants us the freedom to spend more time
    improving Debian; we hope this book to be successful and to contribute
    to this. In the meantime, feel free to retain our services!
    <ulink type="block" url="http://www.freexian.com"/>
    <ulink type="block" url="http://www.gnurandal.com"/>
    </para>

    <para>See you soon!</para>
  </section>
</chapter>
