<cover>
  <title>The Debian Administrator's Handbook</title>
  <!-- Book presentation -->
  <para>
    Debian GNU/Linux, a very popular non-commercial Linux
    distribution, is known for its reliability and richness. Built and
    maintained by an impressive network of thousands of developers
    throughout the world, the Debian project is cemented by its social
    contract. This foundation text defines the project's objective:
    fulfilling the needs of users with a 100% free operating system. The
    success of Debian and of its ecosystem of derivative distributions
    (with Ubuntu at the forefront) means that an increasing number of
    administrators are exposed to Debian's technologies.
  </para>
  <para>
    This Debian Administrator's Handbook, which has been entirely updated
    for Debian 8 “Jessie”, builds on the success of its 6
    previous editions. Accessible to all, this book teaches the essentials
    to anyone who wants to become an effective and independent Debian
    GNU/Linux administrator. It covers all the topics that a competent
    Linux administrator should master, from installation to updating the
    system, creating packages and compiling the kernel, but also
    monitoring, backup and migration, without forgetting advanced topics
    such as setting up SELinux or AppArmor to secure services, automated
    installations, or virtualization with Xen, KVM or LXC.
  </para>
  <para>
    This book is not only designed for professional system administrators.
    Anyone who uses Debian or Ubuntu on their own computer is de facto an
    administrator and will find tremendous value in knowing more about how
    their system works. Being able to understand and resolve problems will
    save you invaluable time.
  </para>
  <!-- Short bios of the author -->
  <para>
    <emphasis role="strong">Raphaël Hertzog</emphasis> is a computer
    science engineer who graduated from the National Institute of Applied
    Sciences (INSA) in Lyon, France, and has been a Debian developer since
    1997. The founder of Freexian, the first French IT services company
    specialized in Debian GNU/Linux, he is one of the most prominent
    contributors to this Linux distribution.
  </para>
  <para>
    A Debian developer since 2000 as well as the developer and maintainer
    of the FusionForge software, <emphasis role="strong">Roland
    Mas</emphasis> is a freelance consultant who specializes in the
    installation and migration of Debian GNU/Linux systems and in setting
    up collaborative work tools. 
  </para>
  <!-- Small paragraph about the history of the book -->
  <para>
    This book has a story. It started its life as a French-language book
    (Cahier de l'Admin Debian published by Eyrolles) and has been
    translated into English thanks to hundreds of persons who contributed
    to a fundraising. Learn more at http://debian-handbook.info, where you
    can also obtain an electronic version of this book.
  </para>
</cover>
