<section>
  <title>Get the book</title>
  <para>
    Before going further, if you want to make up your mind about the book,
    you're invited to <ulink
      url="https://debian-handbook.info/browse/en-US/stable/">browse the
      online version</ulink>.
  </para>
  <section>
    <title>Buy the English Paperback</title>
    <para>
       The paperback is available through Lulu's print-on-demand service
       at a price of €44.90 (without VAT and shipping). <ulink url="">Click here to view
         the book details on Lulu.com</ulink>. Click on the button below to buy it
       directly.
     </para>
     <!-- Here comes a Lulu "Buy now" button -->
  </section>
  <section>
    <title>Download the electronic version</title>
    <para>
      The e-book is available in 3 formats (PDF, EPUB, Mobipocket) and
      multiple languages.
    </para>
    <para>
      The book is freely available because we want everybody to benefit
      from it. That said maintaining it for each new Debian release takes
      time and lots of effort, and we appreciate being thanked for this.
      If you find this book valuable, please consider contributing to its
      continued maintenance either by buying a paperback copy or by making
      a donation via the form below (after having completed your donation,
      you will be automatically directed to the download page).
    </para>
    <para>
      Pick your contribution:
    </para>
    <!-- Here comes the payment form with the list of amounts to choose
         from -->
    <para>
      You can also directly download the book on this page. In that case,
      we hope that you will contribute to the book's success by spreading
      the word around you. Of course, you can always come back later to
      make a donation. 
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <title>Download the book</title>
    <para>
      The book is available in 3 formats and multiple languages (see other
      tabs for translations).
    </para>
    <para>
      The PDF format is the document corresponding to the printed book.
      It's not suitable for reading on small screens. The EPUB format is
      the recommended format if your reading devices supports it (most
      smartphones and many ebook readers do support it). The Mobipocket
      format is mainly for ebook readers that do not support EPUB (like
      the Kindle).
    </para>
    <para>
      Click on the link of the version that you wish to download:
    </para>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem><para>English PDF (30 Mb)</para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>English EPUB (5 Mb)</para></listitem>
      <listitem><para>English Mobipocket (13 Mb)</para></listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </section>

</section>
